HA JUNG-WOO
IM SOO-JUNG
KIM JUN-HAN
KRYSTAL JUNG
SHIM EUN-KYUNG
MAD CONCRETE DREAMS
7TH NATIONAL CHILDREN'S
WRITING CONTEST
The Grand Prize winner of
the National Children's Writing Contest
FALL 1999
came from our school.
Let's welcome the proud winner
Jeon Yi-gyeong with applause!
I don't have a dad.
Other kids have dads,
but there's just me
and my mom at our home.
However,
my mom is stronger than all the dads.
Our house is big.
There's a huge chandelier
in the living room.
Mom always walks with
the click-clack sound of her heels.
If there are no flowers at home,
Mom doesn't go out.
She always brings home
lilies or hydrangeas.
Mom says,
"A home is a person's face.
It must not be messy."
My mom is very cool.
Yi-gyeong, you could become a writer.
You write even better than me.
If you read books every day like me,
you can write well too.
Why say you have no dad?
Is that something to brag about?
Hey, she got an award.
Why say that?
Just write for fun.
Don't even dream of being a writer.
It's just a job for beggars.
Okay, smile!
Smile.
One, two, three!
Okay, let's take one more.
MAD CONCRETE DREAMS
EPISODE 6
Abduction,
murder in a vegetative state...
What's with this family?
Should we do a ritual?
EVIDENCE 3
That's the weapon, right?
Yes
- Bo-ram.
- Yes?
Stand right there.
She got hit
right after she went in.
She just fell over.
And then she was struck again.
What about the landlord?
He's outside right now.
Let's go.
We're seeing each other quite often.
Yes.
I heard you found the body this morning.
What time was it?
I think around 7 to 7:30?
Why did Ms. Jeon come in here?
Do you have any guesses?
Not really.
It's just a simple question,
so no need to worry.
If needed,
a formal investigation will be done.
Okay.
Are we suspects?
Well, right now,
everyone is a suspect.
Oh, I guess that makes sense.
Right.
It will come out
in the investigation.
You have CCTV, right?
Yes.
- May we take a look?
- Sure.
Is this all you have?
Yes.
Why?
Oh, we started using
the CCTV last night.
It was off due to issues before that.
You haven't been using it
and happened to start using it last night?
Yes.
It worked out well.
Thanks to that, the culprit was recorded.
The only entrance
is over there, right?
Yes.
And that's the cafe owner?
I heard the cafe owner
hasn't been seen for days.
Yes, you're right.
Only his part-time workers.
What's wrong?
Doesn't this situation seem strange?
What's strange about it?
The things only happening
in this building.
Hmm, I'm not sure.
Mom! Mom!
Ms. Jeon, just a moment!
Let go!
Ms. Jeon!
Mom!
- Mom!
- Yi-gyeong!
Get a hold of yourself.
Seon...
My mom.
Why is my mom here?
Yi-gyeong.
Oh my! Yi-gyeong!
Yi-gyeong, wake up!
Oh no.
Are you okay, Yi-gyeong?
Yi-gyeong, are you okay?
Seon...
How did I...
Don't you remember?
You collapsed.
Su-jong is preparing the funeral,
so there's no rush.
Just lie down and rest.
Seon.
That storage room...
Storage room?
The basement storage
in your building.
Oh, that place?
What about it?
I was just wondering
if it was there before.
Oh.
Well,
it used to be a storage freezer,
but it broke down.
Now, we just use it
as a storage room for junk.
Why do you ask?
Can you help me up?
Oh, sure.
No, I'll lift you up.
Ms. Jeon Yi-gyeong?
Oh.
You need to stay calm.
I'm fine.
Oh, hold on.
Let me explain first.
So, did you know?
About my mom's situation?
No, not that incident.
You're pregnant.
What?
W-Who?
You fainted,
so we did a routine blood test and...
Is it definite?
I've notified the obstetrics
and gynecology department.
The rounds will be here soon.
- Take care.
- Yes.
Yi-gyeong.
You should eat something.
Think about the baby.
What's wrong?
It's sour.
Mister.
I can't believe this.
How could this happen?
Just the day before,
she was doing fine. What happened?
Thanks for coming.
Yi-gyeong, you have a visitor.
Your mother...
I met your mother before.
Nam Sang-ho, Policy Advisor
at Seoul City Urban Planning Committee
I see...
I pray
she finds peace in a comfortable place.
- This way.
- Sure.
Nam Sang-ho, Policy Advisor
at Seoul City Urban Planning Committee
Mr. Nam.
- Oh?
- Yes.
Please have a seat over there.
Oh, it's been a while.
Let me pour you a drink.
Do you hang out with this kind of guy?
That's a bit harsh, don't you think?
So, Mr. Gi,
have you thought about it?
Yes.
I'm going to ride in the same boat as you.
You made the right decision.
By the way,
do you know that old man well?
We actually have a Go club
in our building.
He's a tenant there.
I see him every day.
Oh, then that guy must know
the Han-maum building very well.
Yes.
How about it?
Can you buy it?
If you bring
that building to me,
I can give you 10% more.
Oh, that would be 10 billion, right?
Depending on dividends,
the amount could go up.
Let's eat.
Oh!
Have you eaten?
Yes,
all the food is delicious.
It's not easy to make good food
at a funeral home.
What about the culprit?
Oh...
You see,
given the current situation,
the cafe owner, Oh Dong-ki,
is definitely the culprit.
Hmm.
We've issued a wanted notice,
so he'll be caught soon.
And earlier,
when I was kidnapped,
didn't you mention something
about the place I was held?
What do you mean?
Coffee grounds.
What?
Coffee grounds were on her clothes.
Oh, that's right.
It's matches up.
Wait, so that means
the cafe owner is the kidnapper.
Wow.
Is this crime connected like that? Huh?
Hey, where are you going?
Mr. Nam Sang-ho?
Yes?
I called for the witness survey,
but you did not respond.
Oh, that police officer?
Hold on, where did you say you worked for?
I'm Koh Ju-ran
from the Yongdaemun Crime Unit.
You knew the recently deceased
Jung Chang-su, right?
Jung Chang-su?
We found your business card
on his dead body.
I mean, is there anyone
without my card in this field?
My card is practically like a flyer.
Mr. Gi, don't you have my business card?
I have mine right here.
Hey! Get back here!
Oh, I'm sorry.
She just gets a bit too eager.
It's fine.
Jeez...
- Honey.
- Yes?
Do you need anything?
- No, I'm fine.
- Okay.
I'll bring the food over.
Sure.
She's pretty bold.
Do young people these days
have no manners like that?
Anyway, Mr. Gi,
I want you to bring
that old man's building.
Got it?
- Yes.
- Okay.
- I'll get going.
- Oh, sure.
No, you don't
have to walk me out.
Good day.
Yes.
I'm heading out.
Yes, take care.
Jeez.
You said you didn't know, right?
What?
Nam Sang-ho.
Do you know an advisor
named Nam Sang-ho?
No.
Who is this guy?
LET'S GO TO OUR BUILDING
RIGHT NOW? DON'T WE NEED TO STAY HERE?
The police are suspecting Oh Dong-ki.
What if they check the restroom?
GOT IT
Yi-gyeong asked
about the storage freezer?
Yes.
All done. This was the last one.
What exactly were they saying?
Do they suspect me or...
Or what?
I guess you could
suspect Oh Dong-ki.
I don't know about that.
It didn't seem like that,
but I think she knows something.
Let's think about it.
I mean, it's clear that Oh Dong-ki
is the criminal right now.
Right.
But what if he gets caught?
If he gets caught,
he'll talk about us.
- That's true.
- Of course.
Then he absolutely can't get caught.
No way. Not now.
Right.
Don't we need
to put Oh Dong-ki
on a smuggling boat or something?
Oh, that scared me.
Hold on a second.
What's this?
Just answer it.
Hello?
It's your fault.
Yes, Dong-ki.
Who's there?
It's me. Seyoon Building.
No one's following you, right?
No.
Oh, right.
You're not bugged, are you?
Come on, why would we be?
If we tell the police,
we'll be in big trouble.
Come in.
Oh, I think it smells here.
Do you mind if we ventilate a bit?
What are you doing right now?
Oh!
Just open the window.
Were you sending some signal out there?
Come on. What signal?
What's with the suit?
Oh,
we just came back from the funeral home.
For the person you killed.
Are you blaming me now?
No, I just answered the question
because you asked.
Anyway, what about the money?
Well, you see...
The police are all over the place,
so we couldn't take out the money.
That's your problem!
Bring me the money, okay?
Before I blow this whole thing up!
Dong-ki,
lower your voice right now.
Just give us a bit more time.
How much time?
One week.
Let's just all die, okay?
Let's die then.
Okay, okay.
I'll get it ready as fast as I can.
Understood?
It's two billion.
But you said one billion?
If you made me suffer like this,
you should at least double it.
But did you treat that hand?
If you leave it, it'll get worse.
Dong-ki.
once you do get the money,
do you have any plans?
I'll handle it myself!
Are you confident
you won't get caught?
Are you scared
I'll get arrested or something?
Of course, I trust you.
Remember that video?
We're a team now.
Get out with that nonsense.
Hey, don't think about
messing with me.
Gosh.
Let's pay him. Set a date.
- What are you doing?
- Huh?
What?
What were you thinking?
You're distracted right now.
You know,
the person who was with me
at that lady's funeral?
Mr. Nam, that policy advisor.
And?
He said something
about the redevelopment.
If we take over Mr. Kim's building,
we're going to hit it big.
But what about Oh Dong-ki?
What are you talking about?
I've decided to join
the redevelopment investment company
that Mr. Nam is working for.
It's completely 100% confirmed.
There's no risk involved.
The returns are over 1,000%.
So you're saying you want to
buy a building without paying Oh Dong-ki?
Are you out of your mind?
So if we pay Oh Dong-ki,
everything will be fine?
What if that guy takes the money
and then blackmails us again?
But he said he would
blow things up if we don't pay him.
Then are you going to bury Oh Dong-ki?
Is that what you want?
I'm just saying
we're discussing this right now.
This opportunity is too good to miss.
This isn't an opportunity,
it's a crisis!
If we mess up, our family is done for!
You say
it's for family,
but all you care about is yourself.
What are you going to do about Da-rae?
Just give up.
It's not like the money we have
is honest anyway.
Let's live within our means.
Ju-ran, is there any point
in us hiding out here?
Will Oh Dong-ki come back here?
Maybe he hid some cash
or something.
But doesn't
something feel a bit off?
I mean, Ms. Jeon is one thing.
But why was Oh Dong-ki in the basement?
It does seem strange.
So I thought about it.
Oh Dong-ki was
trapped in the storage freezer.
Then when the door opened,
he tried to escape and just attacked.
Who locked him up?
The landlord.
Do you think so too?
A while ago,
when you suspected Gi Su-jong,
I wondered why.
But now, with all these things
that keep happening around him...
But why did Gi Su-jong
keep the tenant locked up?
Exactly.
I find that puzzling too.
Do you remember the person you saw
at Ms. Jeon's funeral?
Nam Sang-ho.
Nam Sang-ho?
Who's that?
What happened?
You said you took care
of the accident, right?
My business card was found
on Jung Chang-su's body.
Well?
Is killing people all you guys do?
In that case,
just go out and spread rumors everywhere.
I'm sorry.
You go through all this
and then get insulted.
Does it feel good or bad?
But you see,
there's a reason for it.
Your brains
are not cut out for this.
You work hard
but can't get a regular job.
So when are you going to make money?
Should I call Real Capital HQ?
Are these kids really useless?
I'll make sure
to avoid this mistake next time.
You should have
done better earlier.
Hurry to the hospital.
- Thank you.
- You're bleeding.
Go.
- I'm sorry.
- Yes, hurry up and go.
Should I just
go in and kill him?
That wouldn't be fun.
Sorry. I'll see you tomorrow.
What a carefree guy.
Do you want to have a drink too?
Hwal-sung.
What do you think?
Do you want me to give up too?
Speak up.
If you hadn't made that suggestion
back then,
we wouldn't be in this situation.
What should I do now?
What should I do?
Hey, why did you do that with Seon?
You betrayed your friend and your wife?
Is that fun?
You don't know
Yi-gyeong is pregnant, do you?
Yi-gyeong is pregnant.
Bastard.
You're not even human.
What about you?
Hwal-sung.
Are you okay?
Tell me.
What kind of person are you?
What do you mean? Are you okay?
Want me to tell you?
Seon told me when we slept together.
You have
no confidence.
You're just a worthless poor beggar,
so just give up and confess.
It's the least you can do
to lessen the burden on others.
What did you just say to me?
Hey.
Damn it.
Can't you shut that mouth of yours?
You want to kill me too?
But can you really do it?
Know your place, you loser.
This bastard.
Put in a little more effort.
Oh.
What's this?
What are you doing here?
You just press whatever?
How did you even find me here?
Do you know what happens
when a mouse is stressed?
You put one mouse in a glass box
and give it electric shocks periodically.
Just little shocks, though.
Prickled over and over.
But even with a small shock,
over time,
the mouse got cancer from the stress.
What are you talking about? What stress?
Now let's take two mice
and put them in the same box
and give them the same electric shocks.
What do you think will happen?
Tell me. What do you think will happen?
I don't know.
The mice start fighting each other.
But here's the funny part.
While fighting,
they actually get healthier.
Their fur shines,
and their appetites become huge,
while getting shocked,
even though they get stressed.
Interesting, right?
What's so funny about that?
The pain that doesn't kill me
makes me stronger.
You didn't know?
I guess we're meant to be.
See you again.
What's with her?
HAN-MAUM BUILDING
Hee-ju!
Oh, Mr. Kim!
Hello!
I can get the contract ready right away.
Sell the building.
Not happening.
Mr. Kim!
What should we do?
He's so stubborn.
LAST WILL
Your mother
left all of her inheritance to you.
This is
the last business
she worked on while alive.
SEJEONG-RO GLOBAL REDEVELOPMENT PROJECT
The redevelopment area has changed...
I get it.
And this...
I'm not sure what it is either.
But your mother
said it was her most treasured thing.
I don't have a dad.
Other kids have dads...
It's just me
and my mom at our home.
When I grow up, I'll be a mom.
A mom just like my mom.
I'll stop here for today.
Please continue.
I'm okay with it.
Come in.
Please have a seat.
You're good at finding people, right?
That's my specialty.
I'm looking for that person.
Who?
Oh, the cafe owner?
Yes.
Hmm, if you have
any official documents related to him,
it would make things easier.
I'll get in touch.
If we find him,
shall we hand him over to the police?
Oh, we can do anything
as long as we get paid.
Honey!
Wake up!
Huh?
It's Yi-gyeong.
Answer it, answer it.
Hello, Yi-gyeong?
Oh, Seon,
I'm sorry for calling so late.
Oh, no need to apologize.
Did something happen?
Oh, it's nothing serious.
It's just that something happened
at your building,
so I feel a bit bad.
During the funeral,
I was a bit out of it
and didn't speak much.
What do you mean by that?
You're the one who suffered.
We're the ones who feel sorry.
Yi-gyeong?
Seon.
Can you help me out?
I'm having trouble
summarizing things.
What did Yi-gyeong say?
She sent someone
to personally find Oh Dong-ki.
What is she going to do
once she finds him?
Do I even need to say?
We should give her the paperwork
from the contract with Oh Dong-ki
that she asked for, right?
Did you hear what I said?
Seon.
What?
Do you see me
as a loser too?
Where's this coming from?
What's going on with you two?
Why are you still awake?
Mom, Dad, what are you doing still up?
Da-rae.
Mom and Dad have a lot on their minds.
What's on your mind?
It's hard to explain.
You'll understand when you grow up.
Oh, right.
Aunt Yi-gyeong texted.
She wants to go shopping this weekend.
Seon.
Just trust me this one time.
What exactly do you want to do?
You don't have to worry.
I'll do it right this time.
Well, I'm not really breaking the law.
But why do I feel anxious?
Seon.
I really do want to change.
I'll make it happen for sure.
You just need to help a little.
You're not someone
who can change so easily.
What about the money?
Is it ready?
APRIL 3, BUGWANG SKYROAD
Hey.
I'm saying it again.
If you pull any more nonsense,
I'll expose everything.
Honey.
I brought the documents.
Okay.
Put it on the table there.
Oh, what's this?
Wow, it's so milky white.
This will be revitalizing.
The living has to live, right?
Give it a taste.
Okay.
It's hot.
Wow, it's really rich.
It's so delicious.
- It's good?
- Yes.
Here you go.
Thanks, Seon.
You didn't have to.
In times like this,
you need to eat well.
My mom used
to really love gomtang too.
It's delicious.
Oh, you brought
what I asked for, right?
Yes.
Here you go.
OH DONG-KI
CAFE SINCERITY
Loan Heaven / Will you hand me
the documents today?
By the way, Yi-gyeong,
are you okay?
I'm fine.
I'm not alone anymore.
I'll think of my baby
as the last gift my mom gave me.
I'm going to start over again.
If you need help, just let me know.
Sure.
But, I have a question.
It's about Han-maum Building.
Under investigation
No entry for those not involved
Yes, Hee-su?
Mr. Gi?
I got a call from Han-maum.
They want to meet tomorrow.
What's that about?
Oh, I'll explain when we meet tomorrow.
Just make sure
to prepare the contract well.
Okay.
I'll take Room 605 for my stay.
That will be 50,000 won.
Taxi!
Ju-ran!
SEON: HE LEFT JUST NOW
COME TO GYEONGWON-RO BELLUNA MOTEL
DETECTIVE YOON BO-RAM: I'M ON MY WAY
Police department.
We're currently investigating.
A man with a black hat
just went in, right?
Do you know which room he is in?
Room 606.
Please give me the master key.
WATCH YOUR STEP
Yes, come to Room 606.
OH DONG-KI
This is Oh Dong-ki's room.
What is this?
Ju-ran.
There are a lot of syringes
and strange stuff here.
April 3, Bugwang Skyroad parking lot,
11:30 PM
- Bo-ram.
- Yes?
Look at this.
April 3, Bugwang Skyroad parking lot,
11:30 PM
What time is it now?
It's now.
Driver.
Please hurry to Bugwang Skyroad.
LOAN HEAVEN
Hello?
Are you looking for Oh Dong-ki?
Damn it, why isn't he here?
You didn't bring anyone, right?
We'll all end up dying.
No.
Let's wrap this up fast.
Where's the money?
Quit joking around.
Open it.
Right here?
Yes, right here and right now.
Jeez.
Hey, what are you doing?
It's so simple.
Seriously
Thanks for keeping your promise
till the end.
Sure.
Damn it!
It's fake, you bastard!
You tried to fool me?
Damn it!
LOAN HEAVEN
What's going on?
Damn!
What is this?
Huh?
- Let's go.
- Huh?
Wait! Why me?
Aren't we too late?
Hold on!
Damn it, this bastard!
What's that?
Block it for now.
Damn!
Grab him!
- Come here!
- No!
Don't move!
Damn!
You!
Yoon Bo-ram!
Don't come any closer!
Any closer and I'll kill him!
Drop the gun.
Who do you think you are?
Put the gun down!
Drop the gun or I'll really shoot!
I said put it down!
Drop the gun!
I said put it down
or I'll shoot!
Damn it.
What are you doing?
Pick up the gun!
Damn.
Hello?
Oh Dong-ki is dead.
He's dead?
The police shot him.
The police?
Yes.
I brought two billion
in cash.
Yi-gyeong
says good things about your family.
Oh, I see.
Just because you have a lot
doesn't mean you're happy.
Yes.
Our family
just needs to have enough
to take care of ourselves.
Don't you already have that much?
It'll be just this much.
Your building will be the last one.
Are you sure you can stop?
What do you mean?
Not giving up takes courage,
but when the time comes,
knowing when to stop also takes courage.
Keep this in mind
for Da-rae's sake.
Yes, I understand.
Yes.
Take good care of Yi-gyeong.
She's a special girl to me.
I will.
Congratulations!
You really hit the jackpot at 30 billion!
This is all thanks to you, Hee-ju.
So, am I getting a bonus?
Oh, absolutely.
Let's talk about it outside.
Da-rae,
pick something better, okay?
It's too expensive.
Oh, it's fine.
It's fine.
Excuse me.
Yes?
I'd like
to get this wrapped up.
Sure, I'll take care of that.
Thank you.
It's okay.
- Shall we look around more?
- Sure.
I got a call
from the detective.
They said your tenant was the kidnapper.
Mom, I'll be right back.
Okay, go ahead.
Why would he do
something like that?
For money?
I'm not sure. Well,
it's a world
where people betray friends
and kill their families for money.
All for just three billion won?
Humans are truly pathetic, aren't they?
Don't betray me, Seon.
I could easily
give you three billion won.
Oh my!
I guess it's time for morning sickness.
- Are you okay?
- I'm fine.
Try a morning sickness shot.
It'll help supply nutrition for you too.
Do you know
a place that's good?
Let me introduce you
to a hospital I know.
Just go there and ask for the head nurse.
If you say I'm your friend,
they'll treat you well.
There is no one like you.
YEON HWA-JIN INTERNAL MEDICINE
Head nurse at Yeon Hwa-jin Medicine:
Have you made the deposit?
DEPOSIT COMPLETED
Do you like it?
FOR RENT
Good job.
I have a good eye for people.
I'll do better from now on.
I didn't see this coming.
Hey.
Are you happy?
MAD CONCRETE DREAMS
Check in at Pyeong-buk Gwan.
I want to check
if it's the same drug that was used
when I was kidnapped.
What did you whisper earlier?
Living like this
feels like hell, even now.
So, stop bothering me.
It feels good
to wake up, right?
I need your signature
for asset inheritance.
Are you getting a divorce?
What's going on?
If I get a divorce,
let's start again.
If I convince Pyeong-buk Gwan,
I'll take half the shares.
Do you have a will?
Any last words for your family?